A Finding Aid to the Una Hanbury Papers, 1910-1994, bulk 1966-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hanbuna
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, circa 1924-1985; Series 4; 1 Linear feet Box 4, OV 7
  This series contains sketches, source material, and research on figures, forms, and types prearranged by subject. These materials manifest in news clippings, published journals, ink and pencil drawings, greeting cards, postcards, and scattered photographs and negatives. Oversized subject files are found in OV 7 and include ink and pencil drawings on paper pulled from the files Animals, Miscellaneous; Arms, Hands, Feet; and Bristlecone Pines.
  Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject name.
  - Animals in Art, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Animals, Miscellaneous, circa 1965-1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Oversized material housed in OV 7.
  - Architecture, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arms, Hands, Feet, circa 1964-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Attitudes, circa 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bears, circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Birdbaths, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Birds, 1924-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bristlecone Pines, circa 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
  - Children, 1955-1980 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Clouds, 1959-1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Colin, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Dancers, 1965-1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Designs, Belt Buckles, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Designs, Miscellaneous, circa 1953-1969 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Donkeys and Mules, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Elephants, 1960-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Fountains, 1926-1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Heads, circa 1952-1985 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Muscles in Legs, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Paintings, 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Plants and Flowers, circa 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Race Horses, 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
  - Rocks, circa 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Sambo, circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Sculptures, 1927-1981 (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
  - Seals and Sea Lions, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Secretariat, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Ships, circa 1963-1980 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Oversized Subject Files from Box 4, Folders 2, 4, 9-11, undated (Box OV 7)
- Estate of Una Hanbury, 1990-1994; Series 5; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Estate records document the dispersal--mainly through sale--of sculpture that remained unsold at the time of the artist's death. Saunders Sculpture International and its subsidiary, Perry House Galleries, represented the Estate of Una Hanbury.
  - Accountant, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Advertising, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Appraisal (Bernard Ewell Art Appraisals, Inc., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Art Foundry, Inc., 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Atwell Fine Art, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Barter Account, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bust of Mrs. Ortiz y Pino (Concha), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Client Mailing List, circa 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Consignments, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re: Estate, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1991-1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dancing on the Beach, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Editions, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Inventory, circa 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Diana Hanbury King to Clients (A-B and R), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Laden Art Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Loveland High Plains Arts Council, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Molds, 1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - National Portrait Gallery, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pearson, David, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Potential Customers, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Price Lists, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sales, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Santa Fe Trip Estimate, circa 1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Saunders Sculpture International (SSI) Contract, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Shidoni Foundry/Gallery, 1990-1994 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Vergara Printing Co., 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Wichita Gallery of Fine Art, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Printed Material, 1926-1990, undated; Series 6; 0.4 Linear feet Box 5
  This series consists of articles, reviews, and letters to the editor written by Hanbury; exhibition material including catalogs, announcements, and invitations; publicity consisting of press releases and articles about Hanbury, her work, and the memorial service held for her; and obituaries. The series also includes miscellaneous clippings about friends, acquaintances, and subjects of interest as well as catalogs of sculptors' equipment and supplies.
  Material within each folder is arranged chronologically.
  - By Una Hanbury, 1969-1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Includes articles, reviews, and letters to the editor.
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations, etc., 1965-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1967-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Material concerns friends, acquaintances, and subjects of interest.
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Kildonan News, Spring 1985, and M Magazine, May-June, 1989
  - News Clippings, 1965-1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Newspapers, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Obituaries; Memorial Service, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Publicity, 1926-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    Includes articles about Hanbury and her work appearing in newspapers, periodicals, newsletters, etc. Also includes news releases.
  - Sculptors' Equipment and Supply Catalogs, 1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Photographs, 1910-1991, undated; Series 7; 0.3 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  This series includes photographs of works of art by Hanbury and photographs of Hanbury with family members, as a student, at work, and on her travels.
  The series is arranged into two subseries.
  6.1: Works of Art, 1913-1991, undated
  6.2: Una Hanbury, 1910-1989, undated
  - Works of Art, circa 1913-1991, undated; 6.1; 0.2 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
    Early works of Una Hanbury include loose pages from a photo album documenting work done by Hanbury while studying at the Royal Academy and exhibiting there, annotated with exhibition and prize information. This folder also include works done by her at ages 9 to 11; works done in Capri at ages 15 to 16; Don Quixote, Knight in Armour, and Valkyrie executed in 1920; and some travel photos of Capri from 1920.
    There are also negatives, photographs, and 35-mm slides of miscellaneous works by Hanbury, including an exhibition installation. These folders contain works which may or may not also be present in Project or Subject files but were not placed within the latter groupings in the inherent organization received from the donor.
    - Early Works of Una Hanbury [Rawnsley], circa 1913-1925 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Works, Negatives, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous Works, Photographs, circa 1975-1991 (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
    - Miscellaneous Works, Slides, 1984-1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Una Hanbury, circa 1910-1989, undated; 6.2; 3 Folders Box 6
    Photographs of childhood and youth includes Una at age 6 with a model of a horse (the first photograph of her work); Una with her grandmother and at work on a sculpture in 1915; and Una in class at the Royal Academy in 1925. There is also an undated studio portrait.
    Photographs of Una Hanbury include images at special events include the unveiling of the Gilpin bust in 1973; Louis Rosen's birthday picnic in 1978; the De Lattre inauguration in 1980; the unveiling of Phoenix in 1985; and the opening of the Guild for Religious Architecture exhibition which is undated. Unidentified occasions from 1982 and undated can also be found here in addition to travel photographs of Hanbury in Seville and Alaska[?]; formal and candid portraits, both undated and from 1964; and undated photographs of Hanbury with horses, at Goodwin Ranch, with her family, in her studio, and at a foundry.
    - Childhood and Youth, circa 1910-1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Una Hanbury, circa 1964-1989 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)